Emmanuel Appiagyei

Phone: +1(613) 8078909 | Email: <u>wdappiagyei@gmail.com</u> | Ottawa, ON | LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/wdappiagyei/ |

GitHub: https://github.com/WDverse | Portfolio: https://wdverse.github.io/React-portfolio/

SUMMARY

Full Stack Web Developer leveraging background in Technology Innovation Management to provide an enabling environment for successful digital project development and management. Earned a certificate in Full Stack Development from Carleton University, and developed skills in JavaScript, CSS, React.js, Node.js, and more. Also pursuing a Master of Applied Science degree in Technology Innovation Management at Carleton University. Contributed to team projects where web applications were developed from ideation to completion. Strengths in research, teamwork and collaboration, and project management.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript ES6+, Bootstrap, Handlebars, React.js, jQuery, Git, GitHub, SQL, MySQL, Sequelize, Postgres, NoSQL, MongoDB, Mongoose, GraphQL, Node.js, Express.js, REST APIs.

PROJECTS

Tourist Trap | **GitHub:** <u>https://github.com/WDverse/Tourist-trap</u> | **Live Link:** https://wdverse.github.io/Tourist-trap/

- Summary: Web app providing a city's current weather, hotels, and their addresses.
- Role: Front-end engineerTools: HTML, CSS, JavaScript

Cozy Spaces | **GitHub:** <u>https://github.com/WDverse/cozy-spaces</u> | **Live Link:** <u>https://protected-sierra-59308-f3833016945c.herokuapp.com/</u>

- Summary: Web App for vacation rentals. Built with MERN stack
- Role: Front-end engineer
- Tools: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Bootstrap, React, Node.js, Express.js, MongoDB, GraphQL

Code Quiz Challenge | GitHub: https://github.com/WDverse/Code-Quiz-Challenge | Live Link: https://wdverse.github.io/Code-Quiz-Challenge/

- Summary: Dynamic web page for JavaScript coding questions.
- Role: Sole author
- Tools: HTML, CSS, JavaScript

EXPERIENCE

Warehouse Worker Aramark, Canadian Tire Centre

October 2022 – Present Ottawa, ON

Worked in a large facility to ensure all storages were adequately stocked with food service supplies. Key Accomplishments:

- Reorganized food service supplies in storages, making access twice as easier.
- Ensured food stands had adequate food service supplies on busy game nights, leading to increased sales.
- Made an average of fifteen timely distributions per game night.

Customer Service Representative Farm Boy

May 2023 – June 2023 Ottawa, ON

Stocked and organized fresh produce on store shelves to provide quick and easy access to customers. Key Accomplishments:

- Always maintained an organized shelf of fresh produce, easing access by customers.
- Worked under no supervision two weeks into the job, enabling managers to attend to other matters.
- Assisted an average of twenty customers per shift.

Maritime Officer (National Service Personnel) Ghana Maritime Authority

2019 – 2020

Accra, Ghana

Monitored maritime-related activities along the Greater Accra coastline.

Key Accomplishments:

- Produced reports that accurately described events on during field patrols, ensuring that issues were easily dealt with.
- Took on challenging responsibilities to acquire vital information from shipping vessels.

EDUCATION

Certificate in Full Stack Web Development

Ottawa, ON

Carleton University

Master of Science in Technology Innovation Management

Ottawa, ON

Carleton University

Expected graduation: August 2024

Master of Science in Energy and Sustainable Management

Kumasi, Ghana

Kwame Nkrumah University of Science and Technology

Bachelor of Science in Biochemistry

Kumasi, Ghana

Kwame Nkrumah University of Science and Technology